Ralph E. Flanders Papers
Ralph E. Flanders Papers
- Senatorial Correspondence
  - Jones & Lamson Machine Company
    - Jones & Lamson Machine Company, General, 1947-1954 (Box 107, Folder 4-10)
    - General, 1955 (Box 108, Folder 1-4)
    - Tool Figures (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Special, 1949-1953 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Josselyn, A. H. (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Joslin, Elliott P. (Box 108, Folder 8)
  - J, Miscellaneous (Box 108, Folder 9)
  - Katju, K. N. (Box 108, Folder 10)
  - Kauffmann, Henrik de (Box 108, Folder 11)
  - Kessel, John F. (Box 108, Folder 12)
  - K, Miscellaneous (Box 108, Folder 13)
  - Lattimore, Owen (Box 108, Folder 14)
  - Lee Laboratories (Box 108, Folder 15)
  - Leghorn, Richard (Box 108, Folder 16)
  - Letter to a Generation, Publishers Correspondence (Box 108, Folder 17)
  - Lodge, John (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, David (Box 109, Folder 2)
  - L, Miscellaneous (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - MacNeil, Mrs. Steven (Box 109, Folder 4)
  - Marshall, Peter (Box 109, Folder 5)
  - Mc, Miscellaneous (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - Mehta, G. L. (Box 109, Folder 8)
  - Minnes, & Rudolph V. Hussey (Box 109, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Ideas (Box 109, Folder 10)
  - Morgan, Arthur E. (Box 109, Folder 11)
  - Moutet, Marius (Box 109, Folder 12)
  - Mutual Security Statements (Box 109, Folder 13)
  - M, Miscellaneous (Box 109, Folder 14)
  - National Committee for Effective Congress (Box 109, Folder 15)
  - National Machine Tool Builders Association (Box 109, Folder 16)
  - National Research Council (Box 109, Folder 17)
  - Neuberger, Richard L. (Box 109, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 109, Folder 19)
  - Nicholas, William L. (Box 109, Folder 20)
  - Nienstaedt, L. R. (Box 109, Folder 21)
  - O, Miscellaneous (Box 109, Folder 22)
  - Osborne, Cyril (Box 109, Folder 23)
  - Paget, R. T. (Box 109, Folder 24)
  - Pajus, Jean (Box 109, Folder 25)
  - Peace (Box 109, Folder 26)
  - Pearson, Drew (Box 109, Folder 27)
  - Peisch, Archibald (Box 109, Folder 28)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - Phillips, Hubert C. (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - Polowsky, Joseph (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - Plumley, Charles (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - Politics
    - "Declaration of Republican Principles", 1950 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Politics, 1952 (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Politics, 1958 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Vermont, 1957-1958 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Vermont Senatorial Campaign, 1946 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    - Vermont Senatorial Campaign, 1957-1958 (Box 110, Folder 10)
  - P, Miscellaneous (Box 110, Folder 11)
  - Quartet Camp (Box 110, Folder 12)
  - Q, Miscellaneous (Box 110, Folder 13)
  - Rastall, W. H. (Box 110, Folder 14)
  - Reno, Robert H. (Box 110, Folder 15)
  - Rinehart, Mary Robert (Box 110, Folder 16)
  - Robertson, Wishart McL (Box 110, Folder 17)
  - Romulo, Carlos P. (Box 110, Folder 18)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 110, Folder 19)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore, Centennial Commission (Box 110, Folder 20)
  - Rosenblatt, Maurice (Box 110, Folder 21)
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J. (Box 110, Folder 22)
  - Roston, W. W. (Box 110, Folder 23)
  - Rotary International Certificate (Box 110, Folder 24)
  - R, Miscellaneous (Box 110, Folder 25)
  - Saint Bernard Fish & Game Club (Box 110, Folder 26)
  - Sanderson, Sir Frank (Box 110, Folder 27)
  - Schaurte, Werner T. (Box 110, Folder 28)
  - Scureman, Margaret B. (Box 110, Folder 29)
  - Shrader, James Houston (Box 110, Folder 30)
  - Smalley, Walter B. (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Isabel & Monroe (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Sorokin, Pitrim A. (Box 111, Folder 3)
  - Stough, Harold E. (Box 111, Folder 4)
  - S, Miscellaneous (Box 111, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Norman (Box 111, Folder 6)
  - Thompson, Dorothy (Box 111, Folder 7)
  - Thornton, Dan (Box 111, Folder 8)
  - Tilney, John (Box 111, Folder 9)
  - Twitchell, Carl (Box 111, Folder 10)
  - Twitchell, K. S. (Box 111, Folder 11)
  - Transportation (Box 111, Folder 12)
  - T, Miscellaneous (Box 111, Folder 13)
  - Unesco (Box 111, Folder 14)
  - United States Agencies and Commissions
    - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Information Agency (USIA) (Box 112, Folder 3)
  - United States Departments
    - Department of Agriculture (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Air Force (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Army (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Department of Commerce (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Department of Defense (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Department of Health, Education and Welfare (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - Department of Interior (Box 112, Folder 10)
    - Department of Justice (Box 112, Folder 11)
    - Department of Labor (Box 112, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Navy (Box 112, Folder 13)
    - Department of State (Box 112, Folder 14-16)
    - Department of the Treasury (Box 112, Folder 17)
  - United States House of Representatives (Box 112, Folder 18)
  - United States Senate
    - Correspondence with senators (Box 113, Folder 1-88)
      Senators include: Aiken, Alcott, Anderson, Baldwin, Barkley, Bender, Bennett, Benton, Bridges, Beall, Bowring, Bricker, Butler (H.), Butler (J.M.), Capehart, Carlson, Case, Connally, Cooper, Curtis, Douglas, Ervin, Ferguson, Freal, Fulbright, George, Gillette, Goldwater, Gore, Green, Hayden, Hill, Holland, Humphey, Hunt, Ives, Jenner, Johnson (E.), Johnson (L.), Johnston, Kefauver, Kem, Kennedy, Kilgore, Knowland, Kuchel, Lodge, Long, Langer, Lehman, Lennon, Magnuson, Martin, Maybank, McCarran, McCarthy, McFarland, McKellar, McMahon, Milliken, Morse, Murray, Nixon, O'Connor, O'Mahoney, Payne, Potter, Robertson, Russell, Saltonstall, Schoeppel, Smathers, Smith (H. A.), Smith (M.), Sparkman, Stennis, Symington, Taft, Thomas, Thurmond, Tobey, Tydings, Vandenberg, Watkins, Welker, Wherry, Williams, Young
  - Unsworth, Thomas A. (Box 113, Folder 89)
  - U, Miscellaneous (Box 113, Folder 90)
  - Vacation, Europe, 1955; 1957 (Box 114, Folder 1-2)
  - Vacation, 1958 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Vermont Guild of Old Time Crafts and Industries, 1944-1958 (Box 114, Folder 4-11)
  - Vermont Post Office (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - V, Miscellaneous (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - The White House
    - [General], 1937-1959 (Box 115, Folder 1-9)
    - Arden House Conference (Box 115, Folder 10)
  - Whittemore, W. D. (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Wilson, Charles E. (Box 115, Folder 12)
  - Woods, Capt. E.E., Armed Services Case (Box 115, Folder 13)
  - W, Miscellaneous (Box 115, Folder 14)
- Voting record notebooks
  - 80th Congress 1st Session, 1947 (Box 165)
  - 80th Congress 2nd Session, 1948 (Box 165)
  - 81st Congress 1st Session, 1949 (Box 165)
  - 81st Congress 2nd Session, 1950 (Box 166)
  - 82nd Congress 1st Session, 1951 (Box 166)
  - 82nd Congress 2nd Session, 1952 (Box 167)
  - 83rd Congress 1st Session, 1953 (Box 167)
  - 83rd Congress 2nd Session, 1954; 2 volumes (Box 168)
  - 84th Congress 1st Session, 1955 (Box 168)
  - 84th Congress 2nd Session, 1956; 2 volumes (Box 169)
  - 85th Congress 1st Session, 1957 (Box 169)
  - 85th Congress 2nd Session, 1958; 2 volumes (Box 170)
- Writings
  - Articles and speeches
    - Articles and speeches, 1903-1933; 32 folders (Box 116)
    - Articles and speeches, 1933-1934; 32 folders (Box 117)
    - Articles and speeches, 1934-1935; 32 folders (Box 118)
    - Articles and speeches, 1935-1936; 38 folders (Box 119)
    - Articles and speeches, 1936-1937; 31 folders (Box 120)
    - Articles and speeches, 1937; 23 folders (Box 121)
    - Articles and speeches, 1937-1938; 23 folders (Box 122)
    - Articles and speeches, 1939; 34 folders (Box 123)
    - Articles and speeches, 1940; 17 folders (Box 124)
    - Articles and speeches, 1940-1941; 36 folders (Box 125)
    - Articles and speeches, 1941-1942; 38 folders (Box 126)
    - Articles and speeches, 1943; 28 folders (Box 127)
    - Articles and speeches, 1943-1945; 37 folders (Box 128)
    - Articles and speeches, 1945; 17 folders (Box 129)
    - Articles and speeches, 1945; 21 folders (Box 130)
    - Articles and speeches, 1945-1946; 26 folders (Box 131)
    - Articles and speeches, 1946; 42 folders (Box 132)
    - Articles and speeches, 1946-1947; 39 folders (Box 133)
    - Articles and speeches, 1947-1948; 35 folders (Box 134)
    - Articles and speeches, 1948; 38 folders (Box 135)
    - Articles and speeches, 1949; 33 folders (Box 136)
    - Articles and speeches, 1949; 43 folders (Box 137)
    - Articles and speeches, 1949-1950; 29 folders (Box 138)
    - Articles and speeches, 1950-1951; 34 folders (Box 139)
    - Articles and speeches, 1951; 26 folders (Box 140)
    - Articles and speeches, 1951-1952; 29 folders (Box 141)
    - Articles and speeches, 1952-1953; 34 folders (Box 142)
    - Articles and speeches, 1953-1954; 29 folders (Box 143)
    - Articles and speeches, 1954; 38 folders (Box 144)
    - Articles and speeches, 1954-1955; 29 folders (Box 145)
    - Articles and speeches, 1955-1956; 38 folders (Box 146)
    - Articles and speeches, 1957; 32 folders (Box 147)
    - Articles and speeches, 1957-1958; 26 folders (Box 148)
    - Articles and speeches, 1958; 34 folders (Box 149)
    - Articles and speeches, 1958; 29 folders (Box 150)
  - Books
    - American Century, Harvard University Press, 1950; hardcover, signed and inscribed by Flanders to Syracuse University Library (Box 171)
    - Challenge to World Leadership, Public Affairs Press, 1959 (Box 171)
    - Function of Management in American Life, Stanford University School of Business, 1948
    - Kingdom Come, self-published, 2 copies (Box 171)
    - Letter to a Generation, Beacon Press, 1956; hardcover, signed and inscribed by Flanders to Syracuse University Library (Box 171)
    - Platform for America, Whittlesey House, 1936; hardcover, signed and inscribed by Flanders to Syracuse University Library (Box 171)
    - Vermont History proceedings, vol. 39, no. 1, 1971 (Box 171)
  - Broadcasts
    - Broadcasts, 1949-1951; 54 folders (Box 151)
    - Broadcasts, 1951-1952; 46 folders (Box 152)
    - Broadcasts, 1952-1954; 46 folders (Box 153)
    - Broadcasts, 1954-1955; 37 folders (Box 154)
    - Broadcasts, 1955-1956; 35 folders (Box 155)
    - Broadcasts, 1957-1958; 50 folders (Box 156)
  - Literary manuscripts
    - Ancient Truth In Modern Crisis (Box 159, Folder 1)
    - Flanders, Letters, Manuscript (Box 159, Folder 2)
    - Letter to A Generation (Box 159, Folder 3)
  - Manuscripts
    - 1970? or Sooner, typed drafts (Box 160, Folder 1-3)
    - Our Way Out, typed drafts (Box 160, Folder 4-6)
    - Senator from Vermont
      - Typed draft (Box 161, Folder 1)
      - Appendices (Box 162, Folder 1)
      - Appendices, Part 1 (A - H), Copy 1 (Box 162, Folder 2)
      - Appendices, Part 2 (I - W), Copy 1 (Box 162, Folder 3)
      - April 25 Revision, Copy 2 (Box 162, Folder 4)
      - Deleted from Manuscript (Box 162, Folder 5)
      - Disarmament (Box 162, Folder 6)
      - Illustrations (Box 162, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Chapters (Box 162, Folder 8)
      - Vermont Grandfather, Chapter XVI, Copy 2 (Box 162, Folder 9)
      - Vermont Grandfather, Epilogue, Copy 3 (Box 162, Folder 10)
      - XVI Epilogue (Box 162, Folder 11)
      - Senate Record (Box 163, Folder 1)
      - Setting Copy "Senator from Vermont" (Box 163, Folder 2)
      - Vermont Grandfather Chapter XIV - XVI Senate Life, The Second Term (Box 163, Folder 3)
      - XIV Last Year (Box 163, Folder 4)
      - Bibliography (Box 164, Folder 1)
      - Education (Box 164, Folder 2)
      - Trade Policy (Box 164, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous material
  - Genealogy
    - Miscellaneous, typescripts, notes, photocopies pertaining to the Flanders family genealogy, including a biographical sketch of Pierre Ladoue (1662-1713) by Pomeroy Ladoue dated 1932 (Box 157)
  - Historical
    - Miscellaneous, latter dated 21 Nov 1868 "given to R. E. Flanders by Rolfe Jacobs 8/20/42"; notebook with handwritten title "Jan. 1912 Record of Calculations"; "Tools and Technology" newsletter Vol V no 4 with article and photograph about Ralph and Ernest Flanders (Box 157)
  - Manuscripts (by others)
    - Gearing, Lewis, John L. (Box 158)
  - Photographs, vast majority are prints, but there are a few negatives (safety film)
    - R. E. Flanders, 1938-1958; various locations and events, including SHAPE headquarters, 32d AAA Brigade headquarters at Bushey Hall, England, senatorial appearances, and a few candid photos; some are accompanied by correspondence; in original order and as originally foldered, so folder titles may not match the contents; 12 folders (Box 157)
    - Technical reprints, 1928-1929; reprints of photos and text of various technical items (e.g. turret lathe) (Box 157)
  - Scrapbooks
    See also Voting record notebooks, some of which contain clippings.
    - Newspaper clippings, 1957-1958; 2 volumes (Box 170)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1958 (Box 171)